

# ALBERTO CARLOS CASTRO CASTRO

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I have participated in different projects at an industrial level. More than 8 years of career in which I have worked with multiple programming languages and frameworks I have specialized in Java. Use of agile methodologies (Scrum), UML artifacts as a tool for software modeling, Modeling in databases.

## **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

- Java SE, EE, Spring, Hibernate, JPA, Reactor
- 00P
- Database: Mysql, Oracle, CosmosDB
- MVC, Web Services, REST, SOAP
- Functional Programming
- VCS (SVN-Git-Github)
- CI/CD(Jenkins)
- · Testing and Refactoring.
- UML
- AGILE METHODOLOGIES: SCRUM
- Experience with cloud platforms (AWS, Azure)

## OTHER SKILLS

- Understanding the "big picture" beyond implementation details
- · Great capacity for self-learning
- Good communication and time management
- Ability to work in a team
- Assertive communication
- Implement improvements to increase software efficiency and effectiveness

# **GET IN CONTACT**

Mobile: 312–3347870 Email: ingcastro214@gmail.com
Skype: carloscastro010 Github:https://github.com/Cazcode

Linkeid: https://www.linkedin.com/in/cazcode Medellin, antioquia

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Development Analyst TCS | 2023 - 2023-March

- Implementation of new technologies that allow the solution of problems submitted by the client
- General knowledge of business operation.
- Support and creation of new functionalities to in-house software and third party platforms.

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Development Analyst Java Perficient LATAM | 2021 - 2022-September

- Implementation of new technologies that allow the solution of problems submitted by the client
- General knowledge of business operation

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Development Analyst Java Personalsoft S.A.S | 2018 - 2021

- Implementation of new technologies that allow the solution of problems submitted by the client
- Administrator of software resources that contribute to the optimization of the management of business information.
- Responsible for analysis and development based on the application architecture.
- · General knowledge of business operation.
- Implement cloud solutions for database and software deployments

### JUNIOR ENGINEER

Development Java Corplas S.A.S | 2015 - 2018

- Responsible for analysis and development based on the application architecture.
- Applications support and in-house developments are provided

## **EDUCATION HISTORY**

UNIVERSIDAD DE CARTAGENA - SYSTEMS ENGINEER